[
  {
    "question": "At what age did Bruce Lee die?",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the phrase: 'Is it just me, or is this a ______ train!'",
    "answer": "magical"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the quote: 'Fate does not favor the weak...'",
    "answer": "and indecisive"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which movie is the quote: 'You are not my brother'?"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was Martin Scorsese's first film released?",
    "answer": "1967"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was the animated film 'Pinocchio' released?",
    "answer": "1940"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which TV series does the company 'Pied Piper' appear?"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which TV series is the main character a mathematical genius?",
    "answer": "Mr. Robot"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which film was computer graphics first used?"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which movie was the 'mocap' technology used for the first time?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What award is given for the best Japanese animated film?",
    "answer": "JIFA"
  },
  {
    "question": "What breed of dog is the main character in the animated series 'Boonie Bears'?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterizes French surrealism in cinema?",
    "answer": "Subconscious elements"
  },
  {
    "question": "What device is used to control the movement of a camera along predetermined paths?",
    "answer": "Motion controller"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of James Bond's ship?",
    "answer": "Spectre"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Pandura in the cartoon 'Three Heroes and the Sea King'?",
    "answer": "Dobrynya"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Roman Polanski's 1980 film?",
    "answer": "Tess"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the 2014 film based on Gillian Flynn's book about the mysterious disappearance of a woman?",
    "answer": "Gone Girl"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the 2020 film about unsuccessful robbers?",
    "answer": "Totally Careless"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Indian film about the struggle for independence?",
    "answer": "Lagaan"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Japanese animation award similar to the Oscars?",
    "answer": "Anime Grand Prix"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Russian version of the TV series 'Scrubs'?",
    "answer": "Interns"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the actress who played Paulina Klinger in the series 'Paula'?",
    "answer": "Laura Campagnondo"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the antagonist in 'Monsters, Inc.'?",
    "answer": "Henry J. Waternoose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the award for scientific and technical achievements in cinema?",
    "answer": "Scientific Oscar"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the film based on the novel by Karin Slaughter?",
    "answer": "Buried"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the first Disney animated film produced in IMAX format?",
    "answer": "Fantasia 2000"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the first Japanese animated film?",
    "answer": "Momotaro"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the international film award for achievements in opera directing?",
    "answer": "ECHO Klassik"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the investigation show?",
    "answer": "Honest Word"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the king of the dense forest from the animated series 'Shaman King'?",
    "answer": "Yoh"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the main character in the series 'McMafia'?",
    "answer": "Alex Goodman"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the planet where the events of the movie 'The Fifth Element' take place?",
    "answer": "Fhloston"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the robot from 'Metropolis'?",
    "answer": "Maria"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the robot from 'Station Seven'?",
    "answer": "Yura"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the show where people compete in boat races?",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the song that Mulan sings in 'Mulan'?",
    "answer": "Reflection"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the stop-motion animated film by Wes Anderson released in 2009?",
    "answer": "Fantastic Mr. Fox"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of creating a character's skeleton called?",
    "answer": "Skeletal animation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the runtime of the movie 'Thelma & Louise'?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the technique of non-linear video editing called?",
    "answer": "Non-linear editing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the technology called that captures the movements of real objects for animation?",
    "answer": "Motion capture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is used for detailed renders?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technique was used to create special effects in silent films?",
    "answer": "Double exposure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first animated film created using the stop-motion method?",
    "answer": "The Adventures of a Doll"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first sound film?",
    "answer": "The Jazz Singer"
  },
  {
    "question": "What were special effects made of in silent films?",
    "answer": "Technical tricks"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the idea of an electronic television system proposed?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Annecy Award for animated films presented?",
    "answer": "France"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 2006 film tells the story of Mexican workers in the USA?",
    "answer": "Babel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Brazilian film depicts life in the favelas?",
    "answer": "City of God"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British animated film depicts the life of a toad from the canal?",
    "answer": "From the Canal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which David Fincher film is about a detective investigating a series of murders based on the seven deadly sins?",
    "answer": "Se7en"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Harold Lloyd comedy became a classic?",
    "answer": "Safety Last!"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Martin Scorsese film about a boxer was released in 1980?",
    "answer": "Raging Bull"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actors became popular during the silent film era?",
    "answer": "Max Linder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actress became famous during the silent film era?",
    "answer": "Lillian Gish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animated character by Satoshi Kon can enter dreams?",
    "answer": "Paprika"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animated film tells the story of a magical cow?",
    "answer": "The Cow and the Dream"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animated project received the most awards at the Annecy Festival?",
    "answer": "Gravity Falls"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animation studio is known for films about 'Blastoide'?",
    "answer": "Animax"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animation studio released the film 'Akira'?",
    "answer": "Tokyo Movie Shinsha"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which book by Bulgakov was adapted into a film?",
    "answer": "Heart of a Dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company dominated the color television market in the USSR?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which director won the Palme d'Or for the film 'A Clockwork Orange'?",
    "answer": "Stanley Kubrick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which documentary film festival takes place in Amsterdam?",
    "answer": "IDFA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous franchise is a remake of the Italian film 'Matrix of Fear'?",
    "answer": "Scream"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film about cyber-attacks reached a global audience?",
    "answer": "Citizenfour"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film explores the culture of a tribe in the Amazon?",
    "answer": "Secrets of the Amazon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film has won the most Academy Awards?",
    "answer": "Titanic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film is an adaptation of George Orwell's novel '1984'?",
    "answer": "1984"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film is based on Irvine Welsh's book about drug addicts in Edinburgh?",
    "answer": "Trainspotting"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film is known for its detailed exploration of corruption in the Colombian police?",
    "answer": "Colombian Swing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film tells the story of the MS-13 gang?",
    "answer": "Salvador Today"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film was directed by Cecil B. DeMille?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film was directed by François Truffaut?",
    "answer": "Jules and Jim"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film was produced by Emma Thompson?",
    "answer": "In the Name of the Father"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film was the first to win an Oscar for Best Visual Effects?",
    "answer": "Wonder Man"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former US president organized the 'Political Films' film festival?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which genre focuses on story and characters?",
    "answer": "Drama"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which movie is about a group of scientists discovering a portal to another world?",
    "answer": "Stargate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which movie was produced by Richard Zanuck?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which program is dedicated to investigations?",
    "answer": "Man and Law"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which school used visual metaphors and symbols in its films?",
    "answer": "Surrealism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which show consists of investigations?",
    "answer": "The Investigation is Led by Kolobki"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which show covers family issues and conflicts?",
    "answer": "Family Dramas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which song did Celine Dion perform for the movie 'K-PAX'?",
    "answer": "I'm Alive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which studio created the anime 'Akagi'?",
    "answer": "Madhouse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which studio created the anime 'Cowboy Bebop'?",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Which studio created the movie 'Jack the Giant Slayer'?",
    "answer": "Warner Bros."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which studio specialized in silent films?",
    "answer": "Keystone Studios"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which style uses visual metaphors for deep themes?",
    "answer": "Symbolism"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the music for the film 'Collateral Beauty'?",
    "answer": "Theodore Shapiro"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the music for the film 'Dark Matter'?",
    "answer": "Clint Mansell"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the music for the film 'Donnie Darko'?",
    "answer": "Michael Andrews"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the music for the film 'The Elusive Avengers'?",
    "answer": "Yan Frenkel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the music for the film 'The Social Network'?",
    "answer": "Trent Reznor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who composed the music for the movie 'Joker'?",
    "answer": "Hildur Guðnadóttir"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed 'Soul'?",
    "answer": "Pete Docter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed 'The World Is Yours'?",
    "answer": "Romain Gavras"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed 'Titans'?",
    "answer": "Phillip Aytoun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the animated film 'Shrek 2'?",
    "answer": "Andrew Adamson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who directed the film 'The Fog of War'?",
    "answer": "Errol Morris"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the book 'Amnesia'?",
    "answer": "Chuck Palahniuk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of the book 'To Reach the Clouds', which was adapted into a film in 2005?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the film 'Paragraph 175'?",
    "answer": "Rob Epstein"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the film 'Rear Window'?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the film 'The Sea Wolves'?",
    "answer": "Andrew V. McLaglen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the director of the movie 'The Boys Are Back'?",
    "answer": "Michael Brown"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main character of the animated series 'Foo-Maniac'?",
    "answer": "Foo-Maniac"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the pioneer of CGI in cinema?",
    "answer": "George Lucas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the lead role in the movie 'Ready Player One'?",
    "answer": "Tye Sheridan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the role of Trinity in 'The Matrix'?",
    "answer": "Carrie-Anne Moss"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said: 'Only he deserves life and freedom, who every day goes to fight for them'?",
    "answer": "Goethe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said: 'Plato is my friend, but truth is more important'?",
    "answer": "Aristotle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who taught Jake dragon slaying in the animated series 'American Dragon'?",
    "answer": "Gordon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Golden Bear for the film 'Synonyms'?",
    "answer": "Nadav Lapid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Golden Lion in 2021?",
    "answer": "Audrey Diwan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Palme d'Or at the Cannes Film Festival in 2019?",
    "answer": "Bong Joon-ho"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the screenplay for the movie 'Gattaca'?",
    "answer": "Andrew Niccol"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the screenplay for the movie 'The Princess and the Frog'?",
    "answer": "Ron Clements"
  }
]
